myads.com 2015-12-27

# Rubicon Project Privacy Dashboard and Opt-Out - Rubicon Project

Last Updated: October 21, 2015

Our Privacy Dashboard is designed to assist you in understanding how we collect and use information about you and your device so that you can make informed decisions when using our website and interacting with our products and services.

Only 22% of Internet Users regularly review privacy policies for the sites they visit. That is why this Dashboard does not look like other privacy policies you may have seen. Unlike the average privacy policy which is approximately 2,500 words, the Rubicon Project offers this simple summary.

Like any summary, however, the Privacy Dashboard is not an exhaustive description of our privacy practices and should not be construed to define or limit the scope or extent of our Privacy Policies which can be found at the locations identified below.

**Rubicon Project Privacy Policy and Opt-Out**

To read the full privacy policy governing:

  * how we collect and use data on this corporate website, [click here](http://www.rubiconproject.com/privacy-policy).
  * how we collect and use data through our advertising technology, [click here](http://www.rubiconproject.com/rubicon-project-yield-optimization-privacy-policy).

**Rubicon Project Opt-Out**

To opt-out of the use of our technology to deliver you targeted advertisements based on your interests, [click here](http://www.rubiconproject.com/privacy/consumer-online-profile-and-opt-out/) and [here](http://buyercloud.rubiconproject.com/privacy/opt-out/).

**Data We Collect**

Rubicon Project collects personal information about its users that they voluntarily provide via email or via registration for certain services or newsletters.

Rubicon Project also collects information about you and your device in order to provide you with more relevant advertising. Some of this information, including for example your IP addresses and certain unique device identifiers, may identify a particular computer or device, and may be considered “personal data” in some jurisdictions in the European Union and elsewhere, but this data does not contain any “real world” identifiers such as your name, address, or contact details. When we collect this information through our advertising technology, we use it to help our customers deliver online advertising to you.

**How We Use The Information We Collect**

Rubicon Project uses the information that we collect to provide you with services that you have requested, and to enable our customers to deliver advertisements that we or they believe will be of most interest to you, as well as to prepare aggregate reports that summarize activity and performance.

**Data Sharing**

Rubicon Project may share data with third parties for a variety of reasons, including our third-party advertiser customers, so that they can deliver targeted advertisements to you.

**Changes**

We may change our privacy policies from time to time in order to reflect changes to our practices or for other operational, legal, or regulatory reasons. When we do, we will give you notice of any material changes by posting the revised privacy policy on this website and, where appropriate, by other means.

**U.S.-E.U. Safe Harbor**

We are a participant in the U.S.-E.U. Safe Harbor framework, and in this regard, may transfer certain personal information about you (either as a visitor to our website, or as a recipient of an advertisement delivered using our advertising technology) from the E.U. to the U.S. in compliance with the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles. For more information about the U.S.-E.U. Safe Harbor, please visit <http://export.gov/safeharbor/>. To see our certification, please click here: <https://safeharbor.export.gov/companyinfo.aspx?id=28228>. We additionally protect the information we transfer from the E.U. to the U.S. through inter-company agreements between our various entities.

In accordance with the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles, we have designated JAMS, Inc. as our independent recourse mechanism to mediate any disputes or compliance regarding our compliance with the Safe Harbor. Such mediation will be governed by the JAMS International Mediation Rules. To submit a complaint to JAMS for mediation, please visit <http://www.jamsadr.com/file-safe-harbor-claim/>.

**Contact**

For more information, if you have questions, or if you would like to make a complaint, please contact Rubicon Project by email at [privacy@rubiconproject.com](mailto:privacy@rubiconproject.com), or by post using the details provided below:

**Residents outside of the European Economic Area**

The Rubicon Project, Inc.  
Attn: Privacy Officer  
12181 Bluff Creek Drive, 4th Floor  
Playa Vista, CA 90094

**European Economic Area (EEA) residents**

The Rubicon Project Ltd.  
Attn: Privacy Officer  
2nd Level  
25 Procter Street  
London, WC1V 6NY  
United Kingdom

**Important note:**  The data controller of EEA residents’ personal information is The Rubicon Project Ltd at the above address. The Rubicon Project Ltd is registered with the UK Information Commissioner’s Office (registration no. ZA118130).
